<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2021-04-22T21:09:58-03:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Manifesto</title><entry><title type="html">The Faces of Lidimism</title><link href="/lidimist-faces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Faces of Lidimism" /><published>2021-04-18T07:00:00-03:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T07:00:00-03:00</updated><id>/lidimist-faces</id><content type="html" xml:base="/lidimist-faces/">&lt;link rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; href=&quot;/css/main.css&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lidimistic Manifesto is a solidification of my artistic thinking. It was born out of the disturbance of 
the reality that we see; it was born out of rationality when it was ceasing to be taken seriously and started 
being replaced by personal desires, beliefs, and so-called “alternative facts.” We live in a context where 
people choose their own reality and what they want to believe and recognize as true, and art as a language has 
the role of communicating, moving, registering the moment. It did this in recent times, during the Brazilian 
dictatorship, for example. Since then, we have had solid experiences of this - or distortion of this -, since 
memes started to use jokes to propagate misinformation and create the veil of political knowledge that we see 
in today’s denialists. The Lidimistic Manifesto is an orientation, a counterattack. 
This counterattack, however, can have several faces; I now identify two of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Figurative&lt;/strong&gt; face, defining the idea more clearly, the commitment to identifying forms is more present, 
and the concept is a little more evident. I have understood this face as the most accessible to the general 
public; my &lt;em&gt;Human Evolution&lt;/em&gt; tattoo design from my &lt;em&gt;Historical I, Portrait Collection&lt;/em&gt; series, was made with the 
&lt;em&gt;Figurative&lt;/em&gt; face in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/art/SHST101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; face, where symbolism and complex minimalism - as defined in the Manifesto - are more present, 
the lidimistic commitment is still the same, but there is no need for great clarity in the definition of forms. 
This face is less traditional, and it is there that I see more experimental works, from those using conventional 
means to those that can be defined as cryptoart, being produced. When I created &lt;em&gt;Liberation Through Art&lt;/em&gt; from 
the &lt;em&gt;Dispersions&lt;/em&gt; series, it was in the &lt;em&gt;Abstract&lt;/em&gt; face that I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/art/SDSP101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;drawing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the clear differences between the two faces, I am convinced that they complement each other and are necessary 
for each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post-footer&quot;&gt;
    Written by 
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/rodrigofavarete/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;footer-link&quot;&gt;
        Rodrigo Favarete
    &lt;/a&gt;
    on April 18, 2021
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>